<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Horizon: the realtime, open-source JavaScript backend</title>
        <description>News and updates from the Horizon team.</description>
        <link>https://horizon.io</link>
        <atom:link href="https://horizon.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Write about Horizon and you could win a prize!</title>
            
            <dc:creator>Christina Keelan</dc:creator>
            
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img src="https://horizon.io/images/posts/2016-06-13/banner.png" />
                
                ]]>
                <div><p>Starting today, we’re sponsoring $500 for the best content written about
Horizon during Pluralsight’s <a href="http://tutorials.pluralsight.com/contest/">hack.guides() 2016 Tutorial
Contest</a>.</p>

<p>If you’re not familiar with <a href="http://tutorials.pluralsight.com/">hack.guides()</a>,
it’s a developer community for writing technical guides. It’s a great way to
collaborate with other writers and help spread your knowledge across a growing
open-source community!</p>

</div>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://horizon.io/blog/hack-guides/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://horizon.io/blog/hack-guides/</guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>RethinkDB partners with DigitalOcean for one-click Horizon app deployment</title>
            
            <dc:creator>Ryan Paul</dc:creator>
            
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img src="https://horizon.io/images/posts/2016-05-24/horizon-digital-ocean.png" />
                
                ]]>
                <div><p>Last week we <a href="http://rethinkdb.com/blog/horizon-release/">announced</a> the first release of Horizon, an open-source backend for
realtime web applications. Developers can use the Horizon server and its
frontend client library to build and scale realtime web applications without
writing any backend code. Built on top of RethinkDB, Horizon extends the
database’s built-in support for live updates all the way to the frontend.</p>

<p>To help you get started with Horizon right away, we worked with our friends at
<a href="http://digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> to put together a <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/features/one-click-apps/">One-Click Application</a>.
You can use it to setup Horizon on Digital Ocean, with all of the dependencies
that you will need to get your application up and running. It includes
RethinkDB, Node.js, the Horizon server, and Nginx. You can
<a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-use-the-horizon-one-click-install-image">follow their tutorial</a> to deploy your first Horizon application.</p>

</div>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://horizon.io/blog/digital-ocean-oneclick/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://horizon.io/blog/digital-ocean-oneclick/</guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Introducing Horizon: build realtime apps without writing backend code</title>
            
            <dc:creator>Ryan Paul</dc:creator>
            
            <description>
                <![CDATA[
                
                    <img src="https://horizon.io/images/posts/2016-05-17/horizon-launch.png" />
                
                ]]>
                <div><p>Today we are pleased to announce the first official release of
<a href="http://horizon.io">Horizon</a>, an open-source backend that lets developers build and
scale realtime web applications. Horizon includes:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A <strong>backend server</strong> built with Node.js and RethinkDB that supports data persistence, realtime streams, input validation, user authentication, and permissions</li>
  <li>A <strong>JavaScript client library</strong> that developers can use on the frontend to store JSON documents in the database, perform queries, and subscribe to live updates</li>
  <li>A <strong>command-line tool</strong> that can generate project templates, start up a local Horizon development server, and help you deploy your Horizon application to the cloud</li>
</ul>

<p>The Horizon server is a complete backend that developers can use to power their
applications. It’s great for rapid prototyping: simply run the Horizon server
from the command-line and develop your frontend user experience with the Horizon
 client library. Frontend developers can use Horizon to create full applications
 without writing any backend code.</p>

<p>Horizon is open-source software, which means that you can use and modify it as
you see fit. Run a local instance on your laptop during development and then
deploy your application anywhere you want: low-cost VPS hosting environments,
scalable public cloud platforms, or your own bare metal. Horizon takes advantage
 of RethinkDB’s <a href="https://aphyr.com/posts/329-jepsen-rethinkdb-2-1-5">battle-tested clustering</a>, which makes it easy to scale as
your audience grows.</p>

</div>
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://horizon.io/blog/horizon-launch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://horizon.io/blog/horizon-launch/</guid>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
